<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>master on Jacob Martin</title>
    <link>https://cube2222.github.io/tags/master/</link>
    <description>Recent content in master on Jacob Martin</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://cube2222.github.io/images/avatar.jpg</url>
      <link>https://cube2222.github.io/images/avatar.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 11:51:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cube2222.github.io/tags/master/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Practical Golang: Getting started with NATS and related patterns</title>
      <link>https://cube2222.github.io/2016/06/06/practical-golang-getting-started-with-nats-and-related-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 11:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cube2222.github.io/2016/06/06/practical-golang-getting-started-with-nats-and-related-patterns/</guid>
      <description>Practical Golang: Getting started with NATS and related patterns Introduction Microservices… the never disappearing buzzword of our times. They promise a lot, but can be slow or complicated if not implemented correctly. One of the main challenges when developing and using a microservice-based architecture is getting the communication right. Many will ask, why not REST? As I did at some point. Many will actually use it. But the truth is that it leads to tighter coupling, and is synchronous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web app using Microservices in Go: Part 3 – Storage and Master</title>
      <link>https://cube2222.github.io/2016/03/21/web-app-using-microservices-in-go-part-3-storage-and-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 13:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cube2222.github.io/2016/03/21/web-app-using-microservices-in-go-part-3-storage-and-master/</guid>
      <description>Previous part
Introduction In this part we will implement the next part of the microservices needed for our web app. We will implement the:
 Storage system Master  This way we will have the Master API ready when we’ll be writing the slaves/workers and the frontend. And we’ll already have the database, k/v store and storage when writing the master. SO every time we write something we’ll already have all its dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
